#### Contact

917516742 (Mobile) joaoptamarques@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/jo%C3%A3o-pedro-marques-a039461b (LinkedIn)

#### Top Skills

Hotel Management
Hospitality Management
Hotels

### Languages

French (Professional Working)
Portuguese (Native or Bilingual)
Italian (Limited Working)

# João Pedro Marques

Manager at Pestana Hotel Group

Lisbon Area, Portugal

## Summary

Main Skills:

Operational Management | Guest satisfaction | F&B controller |
Process improvement | Standards development | Leading by the
example | Leading, managing and developing People |
Meeting/Events organizer | Lean Management | Hotel Pre Opening
and Opening experience

## Experience

Pestana Hotel Group

1 year 7 months

Pestana Royal 5\* Hotel Manager - Ilha da Madeira July 2019 - Present (10 months)

Madeira, Portugal

5 Stars Hotel | 313 Rooms | 6 F&B Outlets | 2 Meeting Rooms

Pestana Palace 5\* Resident Manager - Lisboa October 2018 - July 2019 (10 months) Lisboa

Leading Hotel

5 Stars Hotel | 194 Rooms | 5 F&B Outlets | 21 Meeting Rooms

Discovery Hotel Management
Santiago Cooking & Nature 4\* - General Manager
May 2018 - October 2018 (6 months)

Design Hotel

4 Stars Hotel | 32 Rooms | 1 Meeting Room | 3 F&B Outlets

Pestana Hotel Group Pousda Mosteiro Do Crato - Hotel Manager April 2017 - May 2018 (1 year 2 months)

Pousada Mosteiro do Crato a member of Small Luxury Hotels of the World

Small Luxury Hotel

#### 24 Rooms | 1 Meeting Room | 3 F&B Outlets

NAU Hotels & Resorts

Hotel Nau Palácio do Governador 5\* - Resident Manager & Interim Manager

October 2015 - April 2017 (1 year 7 months)

Lisbon Area, Portugal

60 Rooms | 7 Meeting Rooms | 3 F&B Outlets

(Pre Opening and Opening Hotel Nau Palácio do Governador)

Porto Bay Hotels & Resorts

Portobay Liberdade 5\* - F&B Controller

January 2015 - October 2015 (10 months)

101 Rooms | 5 Meeting Rooms | 4 F&B Outlets

VILA GALE, S.A.

(Pre Opening and Opening)

Vila Galé Coimbra 4\* - Resident Manager November 2013 - August 2014 (10 months)

229 Rooms !7 Meeting Rooms | 4 F&B Outlets

Socinger

Hotel Skyna Luanda 4\* - CEO Assistant | F&B Controller | Duty Manager

January 2013 - December 2013 (1 year)

Angola

231 Rooms | 5 F&B Outlets | 11 Meeting Rooms

Tivoli Hotels & Resorts

Account and Finance Trainee (Headquarters)

October 2012 - January 2013 (4 months)

Hotel Ilhamar

F&B Manager (Opening)

January 2012 - July 2012 (7 months)

Abertura da Unidade Hoteleira

Direcção e organização do departamento de F&B

Pesquisa e selecção de Fornecedores

Definição e implementação de padrões de serviço

Programação de Software Back e Front Office (New Hotel)

# Education

ISCTE - Instituto Universitário de Lisboa Master, Management · (2010 - 2011)

Escola Superior de Hotelaria e Turismo do Estoril

Bachelor's degree, Hospitality Administration/Management · (2007 - 2010)